# KARABO MALOKA

# MARKETING COORDINATOR | CREATIVE DESIGNER

Auckland Park, Johannesburg, +27 81 214 7312 karabomaloka92@gmail.com

# PROFILE SUMMARY

Proficient Marketing Coordinator with one year of experience managing strategic marketing campaigns, event coordination, and administrative support. Skilled in UX design, with a strong background in user-centered design, app and web development, and project management. Recently completed an Advanced Diploma in Business Information Technology and currently pursuing a BCom Honours in Information Systems. Excels at blending marketing strategies with technical solutions to drive engagement and improve user experiences.

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Communication	• • • •	Business Acumen	• • • • •
Marketing & Coordination	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$	UX Design & Research	• • • • •
Networking and Relationship	• • • •	Collaboration	••••

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

App & Web Development: HTML, • • • • • • CSS, React Native & Ionic  Documentation: UX Copywriting • • • • •	<b>UX Design Tools:</b> Wireframing, Prototying, Figma, Canva & Adobe Suite	••••
Communication & Collaboration: ● ● ● ● ● Strong relationship-building skills and effective stakeholder engagement.	<b>Project Management:</b> Trello, Jira, CAPM (in progress), PMP (in progress)	••••

# LANGUAGES

English	• • • • •	Sesotho	• • • • •
Afrikaans	• • • • •	SeTswana	• • • •

#### EDUCATION

## **BCom Honours in Information Systems**

Present

University of Johannesburg

**Relevant coursework:** Research, Data Analytics, Cybersecurity, Strategic Management and Information Systems Architecture

## **Advanced Diploma in Business Information Technology**

2024

University of Johannesburg

**Relevant coursework:** Software Requirements & Testing, Database Management, Human Computer Interface & Business Analytics

University of Johannesburg

Relevant coursework: Mobile and Web Development, Database

Management, Digital Business Strategy, Business Analytics

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Marketing Coordinator/ Project Coordinator UJ School of Consumer Intelligence and Information Systems (SCiiS), Johannesburg

March, 2024 - Present

- Managed the school's marketing and administrative efforts.
- Coordinated high-profile events such as the Cybersecurity Event sponsored by AWS, ensuring smooth execution from planning to completion.
- Developed digital content strategies that enhanced engagement across multiple platforms.
- Acted as the primary liaison between the Director and internal/external stakeholders.
- Integrated UX principles to improve digital marketing content and web interfaces for SCiiS.

# Coordinator & UX Design Lead

Feb 2023 - Mar 2024

# UJ Technopreneurship Centre, Johannesburg

- Led UX design efforts for multiple digital platforms to improve user engagement and functionality.
- Facilitated workshops to boost innovation and entrepreneurial thinking among students.
- Contributed to the development of digital platforms like the UJ Incident Reporting Platform.

# Intern Image Retoucher Silo, Johannesburg

March, 2020 - July, 2020

 Edited and enhanced digital images for marketing campaigns and creative projects.

# HONOURS & AWARDS

- Social Media Team Leader TedXUniversity of Johannesburg (2024)
- MC & Facilitator Creatives Meets Techies, AlMashup Hackathon, UJ Women in ICT Webinar
- Artificial Intelligence in 4IR Certificate University of Johannesburg
- UJenius Club Member 2022
- EPF Heritage Hackathon Winner 2022

## VOLUNTEER

- Mobile App Development Expert BRICS Skills Challenge
- Ambassador UJ Technopreneurship Centre
- Career Influencer PsyCaD (Volunteering)
- First Year Marshal University of Johannesburg

# **PROJECTS**

# SCiiS Cybersecurity sponsored by AWS Event University of Johannesburg, 2024

Oct 2024

- Managed event logistics, marketing, and branding for a large-scale cybersecurity awareness event.
- Developed promotional materials and coordinated communication with speakers and partners.

# UJ Incident Reporting Platform University of Johannesburg, 2023

Aug 2023 - current

- Led UX design efforts for a platform that empowers UJ students to report incidents of bullying, harassment, and violence anonymously.
- Conducted user research and testing to ensure platform usability and effectiveness.

# MASS (Master Assessment Scheduling System) University of Johannesburg, 2023

Year long project

- Developed a web-based platform to simplify the scheduling of student module assessments.
- Ensured UX principles were implemented to create a user-friendly experience.

# Website Development Project Johannesburg, 2023

Present

 Designed a personal portfolio website showcasing web development skills using React + Vite, Scss and web design principles.

# REFERENCES

# **Prof Josef Langerman**

**Head:** Centre for Applied Data Science (+27) 11 559 1216 josefl@uj.ac.za

## Ronny Mabokela

**Head:** Technopreneurship Centre (+27) 11 559 2112 rmabokela@uj.ac.za

#### **Refiloe Leeuw**

Coordinator: School of Consumer Intelligence and Information Systems (+27) 11 559 1189/ (+27) 72 818 1688 fifil@uj.ac.za